export const edu101Questions = [
  {
    question: "Teaching is best described as",
    options: [
      "an all-corner affair",
      "a universal activity",
      "rigorous, deliberate, planned, and conscious exercise.",
      "a synonym of instruction, training, indoctrination, and propaganda",
    ],
    correct: "rigorous, deliberate, planned, and conscious exercise.",
  },
  {
    question: "Teaching involves all the under listed except ------",
    options: [
      "establishing the entry behavior of the learner",
      "conveying the teacher as a reservoir of knowledge",
      "guiding the learning activities",
      "evaluating the learning outcomes",
    ],
    correct: "conveying the teacher as a reservoir of knowledge",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is not a component of teaching as a process of communication?",
    options: ["objectives", "teacher", "learner", "content"],
    correct: "objectives",
  },
  {
    question:
      "A process that depends on experience and leads to long-term changes in behavior is known as",
    options: ["learning", "education", "excursion", "training"],
    correct: "learning",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Someone who carries out activities of education, instructions, and teaching is a/an",
    options: ["indoctrinator", "teacher", "chief", "all of the above"],
    correct: "teacher",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Learning can succeed in the absence of necessary instructional materials.",
    options: ["false", "true", "not sure", "totally correct."],
    correct: "false",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One of the following is a condition that must be satisfied before we can say we have successful teaching.",
    options: [
      "It must be mythical (imaginary or not real)",
      "It must be teacher-centered",
      "It must be learner-centered",
      "It must be totally arbitrary",
    ],
    correct: "It must be learner-centered",
  },
  {
    question:
      "In the process of communication, the substitute name for the channel is",
    options: ["evaluation", "learner", "method", "teacher"],
    correct: "method",
  },
  {
    question: "Teaching as a cycle of communication has how many processes?",
    options: ["3", "4", "5", "6"],
    correct: "5",
  },
  {
    question: "Teaching entails",
    options: [
      "arbitraries",
      "promotion of dogma",
      "conscious and deliberate attempt at disseminating dogma without resistance from the recipient learners",
      "conscious and deliberate process of communication of content of instruction by the teacher to the learners.",
    ],
    correct:
      "conscious and deliberate process of communication of content of instruction by the teacher to the learners.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The process of passing information to the learner to carry out some laid down activities by the teacher:",
    options: [
      "indoctrination",
      "self-directed learning",
      "instruction",
      "training",
    ],
    correct: "instruction",
  },
  {
    question:
      "------ is the teacher's guide as to how the whole process of teaching can be approached within a specific time allocated for that subject on the timetable.",
    options: ["lesson plan", "scheme of work", "syllabus", "curriculum"],
    correct: "scheme of work",
  },
  {
    question:
      "is a relatively permanent change in behavior or in behavioral potential that results from experience and cannot be attributed to temporary body states such as those induced by illness, fatigue, or drugs.",
    options: ["indoctrination", "instruction", "learning", "teaching"],
    correct: "learning",
  },
  {
    question: "Indoctrination is a concept synonymous with teaching.",
    options: ["false", "true", "not sure", "totally correct"],
    correct: "false",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Any dysfunction in the process of communication cannot cumulatively affect the process.",
    options: ["false", "true", "not sure", "totally correct"],
    correct: "false",
  },
  {
    question: "To what extent can we say teaching is a profession?",
    options: [
      "Teachers are well-respected and held in high esteem.",
      "Teaching is an exclusive privilege of teachers.",
      "Teaching requires expertise, skills, and competencies.",
      "Teaching enjoys juicy conditions of service.",
    ],
    correct: "Teaching requires expertise, skills, and competencies.",
  },
  {
    question: "How best can we describe teaching in Nigeria?",
    options: [
      "Teaching is a profession.",
      "Teaching is not a profession.",
      "Teaching is an occupation.",
      "Teaching is a halfway profession.",
    ],
    correct: "Teaching is a halfway profession.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Teaching, driving, medicine, engineering, and farming are better described as -------.",
    options: ["professions", "careers", "vocations", "trades"],
    correct: "professions",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The idea that teaching as an activity is one not restricted by professional tutelage is a correct one.",
    options: ["true", "untrue", "half-true", "none of the above."],
    correct: "untrue",
  },
  {
    question:
      "------- is a group of people in a learned occupation. The members of which agree to abide by specified rules of conduct when practiced.",
    options: ["occupation", "work", "labor", "profession"],
    correct: "profession",
  },
  {
    question: "Profession differs from occupation in that ---------.",
    options: [
      "occupation is subsumed in profession.",
      "profession is subsumed in occupation.",
      "teaching is a profession and not an occupation.",
      "teaching is an occupation and not a profession.",
    ],
    correct: "profession is subsumed in occupation.",
  },
  {
    question: "A career is accorded a professional status when ------",
    options: [
      "it applies for it at the ministry of labor.",
      "it involves the use of formal languages.",
      "it involves a long period of training.",
      "it involves a certificate of proficiency.",
    ],
    correct: "it involves a long period of training.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The anticipated learning outcomes in classroom instruction is known as ------",
    options: [
      "behavioral objectives",
      "broad objectives",
      "goals",
      "benchmark",
    ],
    correct: "behavioral objectives",
  },
  {
    question: "What makes instructional objectives measurable?",
    options: [
      "amount of time",
      "amount of material",
      "amount of resources",
      "amount of knowledge",
    ],
    correct: "amount of knowledge",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Cognitive, affective, and psychomotor domains of learning respectively imply -------",
    options: [
      "knowledge, feelings, and movement of the body",
      "knowledge, attitude, and manipulation",
      "cognition, emotion, and manipulation",
      "intelligence, emotion, and movement of the body",
    ],
    correct: "knowledge, feelings, and movement of the body",
  },
  {
    question:
      "It relates to the recall of factual information. This statement describes --------",
    options: ["Knowledge", "comprehension", "application", "analysis"],
    correct: "Knowledge",
  },
  {
    question:
      "This relates to the acceptance of worth attached to an object, idea, or concept. This assertion describes ---------",
    options: ["responding", "valuing", "organization", "receiving"],
    correct: "valuing",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Objectives and evaluation are complementary in the following ways except --------",
    options: [
      "objectives provide direction for evaluation.",
      "evaluation improves the quality of objectives",
      "objectives protect the quality of evaluation.",
      "evaluation validates instructional objectives",
    ],
    correct: "objectives protect the quality of evaluation.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "All of the following except one are appropriate methods of questioning for synthesis as a cognition level.",
    options: ["integrate", "interpret", "modify", "create"],
    correct: "modify",
  },
  {
    question: "The highest level of the psychomotor domain is -----------",
    options: [
      "basic movement",
      "physical ability",
      "non-discursive communication",
      "perpetual ability",
    ],
    correct: "non-discursive communication",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The willingness of the learner to react to the stimulus perceived is a description of ----------",
    options: ["organization", "valuing", "responding", "receiving"],
    correct: "responding",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What, label, collect, when, and identify are appropriate clues for -------",
    options: ["knowledge", "perception", "comprehension", "analysis"],
    correct: "knowledge",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Adopt, enforce, preserve, endorse, contribute are appropriate verbs suitable for the description of ----------",
    options: ["receiving", "responding", "valuing", "organization"],
    correct: "responding",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of these is not a hierarchical level of affective objective?",
    options: ["receiving", "responding", "valuing", "reflection"],
    correct: "reflection",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Holding a pen to write and using a hand fork by a school pupil are typical examples of -------",
    options: [
      "basic fundamental movement",
      "skilled movement",
      "reflex movement",
      "physical abilities",
    ],
    correct: "basic fundamental movement",
  },
  {
    question:
      "All but one of the following is appropriate. At the end of the lesson, the students should be able to:",
    options: [
      "state five characteristics of living things",
      "understand five characteristics of living things",
      "know five characteristics of living things",
      "demonstrate five characteristics of living things",
    ],
    correct: "state five characteristics of living things",
  },
  {
    question:
      "----- can be described as noticeable behavioral change that should manifest in a learner after being exposed to a period of instruction.",
    options: [
      "scheme of work",
      "instructional materials",
      "instruction",
      "instructional objectives",
    ],
    correct: "instructional materials",
  },
  {
    question:
      "-------- provide a specific statement of what pupils will do at the end of instruction.",
    options: ["aims", "objectives", "missions", "goals"],
    correct: "objectives",
  },
  {
    question: "----- are general statements of intentions.",
    options: ["aims", "goals", "objectives", "missions"],
    correct: "goals",
  },
  {
    question: "----- state how the intent may be realized.",
    options: ["aims", "goals", "objectives", "missions"],
    correct: "objectives",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The domain that is concerned with the impact of knowledge and thinking skills of learners is -----",
    options: ["affective", "cognitive", "psychomotor", "emotional"],
    correct: "cognitive",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The assessment of the extent to which the teaching-learning process has been gratified or realized is -----",
    options: ["introspection", "assessment", "evaluation", "appraisal"],
    correct: "evaluation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One of these is not a guideline for effective questioning technique.",
    options: [
      "Questions should be posted at the entire class.",
      "Questions should not be ambiguous.",
      "Chorus answers to questions should not be entertained.",
      "Questions should be of higher-order level of cognition.",
    ],
    correct: "Questions should be of higher-order level of cognition.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of these is not an advantage of questioning technique in classroom instruction?",
    options: [
      "It makes the teacher more relaxed and free from stress.",
      "It promotes meaningful classroom dialogue.",
      "It makes learners more alert in the classroom.",
      "It helps to keep the teaching-learning process on track.",
    ],
    correct: "It makes the teacher more relaxed and free from stress.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Why should a teacher not engage in the habit of not repeating the questions asked in classroom instruction?",
    options: [
      "to make the teacher save energy",
      "to make the learner develop good listening skills",
      "to punish the learners for not listening",
      "to make the teacher command respect from the learners",
    ],
    correct: "to make the learner develop good listening skills",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is not a quality of a good question?",
    options: [
      "It must be clearly stated.",
      "It must be in sequence.",
      "It must be stated audibly.",
      "It must be apathetic.",
    ],
    correct: "It must be apathetic.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One of the guidelines for good questioning techniques in classroom instruction is that it -----",
    options: [
      "must not be double-barreled",
      "must be limited to brilliant teachers.",
      "must reflect a high level of language.",
      "must satisfy the interest of the learners.",
    ],
    correct: "must not be double-barreled",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of the following is not an appropriate teaching method at the primary school?",
    options: [
      "lecture method",
      "discussion method",
      "discovery method",
      "demonstration method",
    ],
    correct: "lecture method",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of these is not a teaching method?",
    options: [
      "Problem-solving",
      "Team teaching",
      "Field trip",
      "Teaching for cooperative learning",
    ],
    correct: "Teaching for cooperative learning",
  },
  {
    question:
      "It provides firsthand experience of what is taught in the classroom. This statement relates to:",
    options: [
      "Play way method",
      "Field trip method",
      "Discussion method",
      "Team teaching method",
    ],
    correct: "Field trip method",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The teaching method that involves continuous delivery of content by the teacher is ------",
    options: [
      "Discussion method",
      "Lecture method",
      "Dramatization method",
      "Demonstration method",
    ],
    correct: "Lecture method",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The teaching method in which two or more teachers are involved in the teaching of a subject according to their expertise and competence is known as ------",
    options: [
      "Play way method",
      "Concept mapping",
      "Team teaching method",
      "Teaching for cooperative learning",
    ],
    correct: "Team teaching method",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which of these is most suitable for teaching addition with carrying in mathematics to a primary two class?",
    options: [
      "play way methods",
      "lecture method",
      "Field trip method",
      "Discussion method",
    ],
    correct: "play way methods",
  },
  {
    question: "Team teaching entails ------",
    options: [
      "arrangement of pupils into two groups for a contest.",
      "use of two or more teachers for a particular subject.",
      "invitation of external subject specialists.",
      "illustration involving the use of different interest groups.",
    ],
    correct: "use of two or more teachers for a particular subject.",
  },
  {
    question: "One of the following is the odd one.",
    options: [
      "lecture method",
      "team teaching method",
      "excursion method",
      "acoustic method",
    ],
    correct: "acoustic method",
  },
  {
    question: "The two types of motivation are ------- and ------------.",
    options: [
      "extrinsic and intrinsic",
      "external and internal",
      "exterior and interior",
      "within and without",
    ],
    correct: "extrinsic and intrinsic",
  },
  {
    question: "In the theory of motivation, as one need is gratified -------",
    options: [
      "individual needs become satisfied.",
      "other needs are gratified.",
      "a higher need comes up.",
      "the individual becomes accepted.",
    ],
    correct: "a higher need comes up.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "One of the underlying assumptions of motivation is that the previously gratified need becomes secondary and ------",
    options: [
      "so many are always in a state of need.",
      "many others become primary and complex.",
      "too inconsequential to warrant any special attention.",
      "insignificant to many people.",
    ],
    correct: "too inconsequential to warrant any special attention.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "He is enthusiastic to learn, can handle abstractions, and is always ready to take up challenges. The above perfectly describes ------.",
    options: [
      "an emotional learner.",
      "a well-motivated learner.",
      "a high potential learner.",
      "a learner with a level of cognition.",
    ],
    correct: "a well-motivated learner.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "According to Maslow, human needs can be categorized into ------ and ---------.",
    options: [
      "growth and development needs",
      "growth and deficiency needs",
      "social and basic needs",
      "physical and spiritual needs",
    ],
    correct: "growth and deficiency needs",
  },
  {
    question: "Need for love, affection, and recognition indicate ----------",
    options: [
      "Psychological needs",
      "safety needs",
      "social needs",
      "self-esteem",
    ],
    correct: "social needs",
  },
  {
    question: "The peak of Maslow's theory hierarchy of need is --------",
    options: [
      "self-actualization needs",
      "self-esteem needs",
      "social needs",
      "safety needs",
    ],
    correct: "self-actualization needs",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The application of theories of motivation to classroom instruction involves ------",
    options: [
      "the use of negative reinforcement only.",
      "the use of positive reinforcement only",
      "efforts from teachers making his subject interesting",
      "indiscriminate use of incentives by the teacher.",
    ],
    correct: "efforts from teachers making his subject interesting",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of these is not true about motivation?",
    options: [
      "Every human being is always in a state of need.",
      "The state of complete satisfaction is unattainable.",
      "All human needs can be satisfied.",
      "As one need is gratified, a higher need comes up.",
    ],
    correct: "All human needs can be satisfied.",
  },
  {
    question:
      "An individual who decided to pursue a post-graduate program is probably seeking the satisfaction of -------",
    options: [
      "safety need",
      "social need",
      "esteem need",
      "self-actualization need",
    ],
    correct: "self-actualization need",
  },
  {
    question:
      "The inner urge or drive that accounts for the arousal, selection, direction, and continuation of behavior is --------",
    options: ["intelligence", "instinct", "motivation", "none of the above."],
    correct: "motivation",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To retain learners in school, the following should be observed except.",
    options: [
      "school environment should be triadic",
      "instructional materials should be available",
      "the time school opens should be flexible",
      "teachers should be friendly and accommodating",
    ],
    correct: "the time school opens should be flexible",
  },
  {
    question:
      "To achieve optimum impact in the classroom, a teacher needs to -----",
    options: [
      "be aggressive",
      "be domineering",
      "provide necessary conditions that will enhance learning",
      "all of the above.",
    ],
    correct: "provide necessary conditions that will enhance learning",
  },
];
